

// data.js


const data = [
    {
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "What are the fundamental types of software products?",
  answer: "generic and customized"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Which of the following is not an essential attribute of good software?",
  answer: "Affordability"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Computer science and software engineering are the same discipline: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Which of the following is not a general issue that affects many different types of software?",
  answer: "Value"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Which of the following is not a fundamental activity in software processes?",
  answer: "software estimation"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Which of the following is not an issue of professional responsibility?",
  answer: "Salary"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Even when following all ethical principles, ethical dilemmas can occur: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "One of the ethical principles of the ACM/IEEE code of ethics is that software engineers shall be competitive, there is no need to be fair and supportive of colleagues: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Software engineering is an engineering discipline that is concerned with all aspects of software production from the early stages of system specification through to maintaining the system after it has gone into use: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 1",
  question: "Systems should be developed using a managed and understood development process: one process fits all: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "It is increasingly irrelevant to distinguish between software development and evolution: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Process descriptions may include pre- and post-conditions, which are statements that are true before and after a process activity has been enacted or a product produced: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "In the SEI Capability Maturity Model which level denotes that process improvement strategies have been defined and are being used?",
  answer: "optimizing"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "An advantage of the waterfall model is the ease of accommodating change after the process is underway: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Which of the following is not a stage of testing?",
  answer: "value testing"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Requirements engineering is the process of developing a software specification: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Agile processes are processes where all of the process activities are planned in advance and progress is measured against this plan: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "One approach to reducing the costs of rework is 'change anticipation', where the process is designed so that changes can be accommodated at relatively low cost: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Component adaptation and integration is a key stage of which software process model?",
  answer: "integration and configuration"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 2",
  question: "Programming is an individual activity with no standard process: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "In Extreme Programming, user requirements are expressed as user stories or scenarios. They are not documented but broken into tasks. These tasks are the basis of schedule and cost estimates: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Extreme Programming (XP) takes an 'extreme' approach to iterative development: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "In scrum, which term matches this definition: 'An individual (or possibly a small group) whose job is to identify product features or requirements, prioritize these for development and continuously review the product backlog to ensure that the project continues to meet critical business needs'?",
  answer: "product owner"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Consider this description of programming practices: 'Large amounts of overtime are not considered acceptable as the net effect is often to reduce code quality and medium term productivity'. Which term is used in Extreme Programming for this practice?",
  answer: "sustainable pace"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Agile development is a plan driven approach: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Which of the following is not a principle of Agile methods?",
  answer: "process focus"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "In Pair Programming, 2 programmers are paired up for the duration of the complete project: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Which of the following is not an example of re-factoring?",
  answer: "the coding of a low-level device driver in assembly language"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "Which of the following is not part of the Agile Manifesto?",
  answer: "comprehensive documentation over working software"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 3",
  question: "'Scaling up' is concerned with how agile methods can be introduced across a large organization with many years of software development experience: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "The requirements engineering process is an iterative process that includes requirements elicitation, specification and validation: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "Many agile methods argue that producing detailed system requirements is a waste of time: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "The software requirements document should set out WHAT the system should do rather than HOW it should do it: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "The system design model is generated during the requirements engineering process: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "Which of the following is not a generic activity in the requirements engineering process?",
  answer: "modeling"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "Which of the following is not a metric for specifying nonfunctional requirements?",
  answer: "Luck"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "System managers cannot be system stakeholders: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "The requirements engineering process can be viewed as a spiral: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "Which of the following is not a problem in requirements elicitation?",
  answer: "Stakeholders know what they really want."
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 4",
  question: "Which of the following is not a type of requirement?",
  answer: "Environmental concerns"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "Which of the following is not an essential model when modeling systems?",
  answer: "Consequential model"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "The notation '1..*' at the end of an association between classes means?",
  answer: "at least 1 object participates in the association"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "Which of the following is not a UML diagram type?",
  answer: "data flow"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "Which of the following should be in a tabular description of a use case?",
  answer: "Actors, description, data, stimulus, response, comments"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "A use case must have at least one actor: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "Each use case represents a discrete task that involves external interaction with a system: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "UML stands for Universal Manufacturing Model: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "In the context of graphical models, incomplete and incorrect models are OK as their role is to support discussion: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "What is not usually shown on a sequence diagram?",
  answer: "subclass"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 5",
  question: "UML activity diagrams may be used to define business process models: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Which of the following is not a question asked to make architectural decisions?",
  answer: "Which programming language should be used?"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Which item is not usually part of an architectural pattern description?",
  answer: "cost"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Patterns are a means of representing, sharing and reusing knowledge: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "The MVC architectural pattern contains:",
  answer: "model, view, controller"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "The 4+1 views of system architecture include:",
  answer: "logical, physical, development, process"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Architecture in the large is concerned with the architecture of individual programs. At this level, we are concerned with the way that an individual program is decomposed into components: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "The pipe and filter architectural pattern originated in the UNIX operating system: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Which of the following is not an advantage of explicit architecture?",
  answer: "Performance Improvement"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "An architectural pattern is a stylized description of a new design practice, which has not been tried and tested yet: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 8",
  question: "Architectural design is concerned with understanding how a software system should be organized and designing the overall structure of that system: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Which of the following is not a level of reuse?",
  answer: "layer level"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Which of the following plays no role in the Observer pattern?",
  answer: "bystander"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "A system context model is a structural model that demonstrates the other systems in the environment of the system being developed: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Which of the following is not an approach to object identification?",
  answer: "scrabble"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "A UML diagram type where objects are arranged horizontally across the top of the page is called?",
  answer: "sequence diagram"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "In object-oriented design you need a state diagram for all of the objects in the system: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Software design and implementation activities are never inter-leaved: True/False?",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Which of the following is not a common activity during the object-oriented design process?",
  answer: "Consider stakeholder constraints"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "A so-called 'reciprocal' license means that if you use open-source software then you must make that software also open source: True/False?",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 9",
  question: "Who is Christopher Alexander?",
  answer: "influential architect and design theorist"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Whenever possible, unit testing should be automated so that tests are run and checked with manual intervention:",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Use cases developed to identify system interactions are not useful as a basis for system testing:",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Program testing can reveal the absence of errors not their presence.",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Software inspection is:",
  answer: "Concerned with analysis of the static system representation to discover problems"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Which of the following is not part of development testing?",
  answer: "Acceptance testing"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Verification means \"Are we building the product right\", whereas validation means \"Are we building the right product\".",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Which of the following is not a stage of testing?",
  answer: "Equivalence testing"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Which of the following is not a general testing guideline?",
  answer: "Avoid computation results to be too large or too small"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Which of the following is not usually subject to inspection as part of the verification and validation process?",
  answer: "System prototype"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 10",
  question: "Object class testing is a form of unit testing:",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Legacy systems are older systems that rely on languages and technology that are no longer used for new systems development.",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Refactoring involves modifying a program to improve its structure, reduce its complexity or make it easier to understand by adding new functionality.",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Urgent changes must be implemented by going through all stages of the software engineering process.",
  answer: "False"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Which of the following causes risk in legacy system replacement?",
  answer: "all of the above"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Which of the following is not an issue in business value assessment when assessing a legacy system?",
  answer: "Supplier stability"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Which of the following may cause software change?",
  answer: "all of the above"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "The software evolution process does not depend on which of the following?",
  answer: "The market capitalization of the corporation"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Which of the following is not a typical component of a legacy system?",
  answer: "Interactive development environment"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "The majority of the software budget in large companies is devoted to changing and evolving existing software rather than developing new software.",
  answer: "True"
},
{
  quiz: "Quiz 11",
  question: "Which of the following is the correct sequence of activities in the emergency repair process?",
  answer: "Analyze source code, modify source code, delivery modified system"
}

];